- Get her arms.
- I got this side.
- 抓她的手.
- 我抓这边.
Miss PuIaski?
珀拉斯奇小姐?
- Cover her arms.
- Miss PuIaski, caIm down now.
- 把手盖好.
- 珀拉斯奇小姐, 放松放松.
It's okay. It's gonna be aII right.
好的. 很快就没事了.
- Get her Iegs.
- I got it. Hang on.
- 抓住她脚.
- 抓住了. 坚持住.
Miss PuIaski,
just caIm down, pIease.
珀拉斯奇小姐,
保持镇定, 放松.
- You're aII right.
- Give her a sedative.
- 你会没事.
- 给她注射镇静剂.
No! No!
不! 不!
Ronette puIIed out her IV.
I just gave her a sedative.
朗尼特把针管都拔掉了.
刚刚给她打了镇静剂.
Looks Iike dye.
像给染过色.
- Harry, give me a hand.
- What's this?
- 哈里, 帮我一下.
- 这是什么?
A IittIe chIoride.
Spray her finger.
喷一点氯化液.
在她的手指上.
AIbert, get your microscope.
艾伯特, 把显微镜拿来.
AII right.
好的.
AII right, Ronette.
Breathe, now, honey.
好的, 朗尼特.
深呼吸, 来, 宝贝.
- He's been here.
- We have a 24-hour guard.
- 他来过这.
- 可我们有人24小时监护.
Harry, he did this.
哈里, 是他干的.
And he tainted the IV.
还把她的点滴污染了.
Maybe she saw him.
也许她看到他.
Maybe she heard a Sousa march
and got up to Iook for her baton.
也许，她听到苏沙军号，
起来找她的指挥棒呢.
I'II do a workup on the IV.
我去看点滴包上有没有留下痕迹.
That's our man.
这才像话.
Those Ietters were never made pubIic.
这些字母还没公开过.
FeIIas,
各位,
Iet's stand together for a moment.
让我们暂时统一战线.
It's time I mentioned something.
有些事该告诉你们了.
Now, I'm not sure,
现在, 我还不是很确定,
but I beIieve I was visited by a giant.
但我确信，我亲眼见过一个巨人.
Twice.
2次了.
In my room.
就在我房间里.
He Ieft me three cIues.
他给我留下了一些线索.
The first had to do with
Jacques RenauIt in a body bag.
第一，他说
雅克·雷诺会死.
It came true aImost immediateIy.
这个几乎立刻就应验了.
The second was,
''The owIs are not what they seem.''
第二,
''不要被猫头鹰的外表迷惑了.''
The third was about a man
who points without chemicaIs.
第三是不要给他用药
他就会指引你.
You were visited by a giant?
什么，你看到了一个巨人?
Any reIation to the dwarf?
那有看到小侏儒吗?
You're wearing a different sweater
than yesterday.
你今天的衣服比
昨天的好看多了.
CoIor's better on you.
颜色很配你.
I forgot my manners.
哦，都忘了介绍呢.
I'm HaroId Smith.
我是哈罗德·史密斯.
I guess you know who I am.
你应该知道我是谁了吧.
PIease come in.
快请进.
WouId you Iike some Iemonade?
来杯柠檬水怎样?
I aIso have some saItines
and some appIe butter.
我还有苏打饼
和苹果酱.
Or wouId you
Iike to wash your hands?
要不你
先去洗洗手?
No, thanks.
哦, 不用了.
I insist.
那请坐吧.
It's very warm in here.
这里真暖和.
- Don't be nervous, Donna.
- I'm not nervous.
- 别紧张, 唐娜.
- 我没有.
I'm curious.
只是好奇.
Curious about my reIationship
with Laura.
好奇我和劳拉
的关系吗.
Why did you send me that Ietter?
你为什么寄那封信给我?
Laura wanted me to get in touch with
you if anything ever happened to her.
她说万一她出了什么事
可以和你联系的.
Why?
为什么?
She said you'd ask
a Iot of questions.
她说你会问
很多问题.
How Iong did you know Laura?
你和劳拉认识多久了?
Ever since she began
MeaIs on WheeIs.
从她来送餐开始
就认识了.
I was her best customer.
我是她最好的客人.
You don't seem
much Iike a shut-in.
你不像个
孤僻的人.
You mean, poIiteIy,
what's the matter with me?
很婉转, 你是想问,
我为什么把自己关在这里吧?
Okay.
是的.
I don't Iike to go outside.
我不喜欢到外面去.
I...
我...
...can't.
...不能.
Do you have a judgment
you'd Iike to express?
你肯定觉得
我是个怪人吧?
No.
没有.
Laura said you were very fair-minded.
劳拉告诉过我你是个很正直的人.
If you knew her so weII, why didn't she
ever mention you to me?
既然你们认识这么久了，为什么
她从没向我提起过你?
WeII, Laura Iiked to think of me...
嗯, 劳拉更喜欢...
...as a mystery in her Iife.
...我做个神秘人.
Then why did you caII me?
那现在为什么又叫我来?
I am--
我--
WeII, I used to be a horticuIturist.
呃, 我以前是个园艺家.
I raise orchids.
我种兰花.
That's why it's so warm in here.
所以这里很暖.
They don't need a Iot of Iight.
兰花不需要太多光线.
I wrote to you because I wondered
我叫你来是因为
if you'd be kind enough
to pIace one of them on her grave.
希望你能为我在她的墓前
献上一朵兰花.
Of course.
当然.
- WiII you excuse me a moment?
- Sure.
- 我失陪一会儿?
- 没事.
This is a hybrid.
这是个杂交品种.
- A Iady's sIipper.
- It's very beautifuI.
- 欧洲芍兰.
- 真美.
Take it, pIease.
My Iast gift to Laura.
来, 拿好.
我送给劳拉最后的礼物.
That's very kind of you, Mr. Smith.
史密斯先生, 你真好.
HaroId.
叫我哈罗德.
She was very kind to me.
她对我也很好.
Forgive me, but I know so much
about you, you see.
原谅我, 我知道很多你的事
你看.
What?
什么?
You're every bit as IoveIy
as Laura said you were.
你就跟劳拉形容的
一样可爱.
I'II be back.
我会再来的.
I'II be here.
我会等你的.
R, B, T.
Harry, I beIieve that these Ietters
and the Giant's cIues
哈里, 我认为这几个字母
和巨人给我的暗示
are in some way reIated
to this Iong-haired man.
都在某种程度上
和这个长发男有关联.
Mrs. PaImer saw him in a vision.
帕尔默太太就梦见过他.
She caIIed this morning
to say that Maddy
她今早打电话来说
马蒂前两天
had seen the man twice
in the past two days,
也见过他
两次了,
both times in a vision.
梦见的.
I've seen him in my dream.
我也梦见过他.
And Ronette.
还有朗尼特.
- Saw him physicaIIy at the train car.
- Right.
- 是亲眼在火车那里见过他的.
- 对.
Four of us have seen him
in different forms.
我们四个都以
不同形式见过他.
This path is a psychic Iink
that wiII Iead us straight to him.
就像是心灵感应
会帮我们抓到他的.
So, what did this giant sound Iike?
那, 巨人说话时是什么声音?
I mean, did he have
a big, booming voice or what?
我是说, 又低又沉吗
听不清，还是怎样?
- No, no. He spoke softIy, distinctIy.
- And you gave him the beans
- 不, 不. 很温和, 很清晰.
- 然后他就给了你一些豆
you were supposed to use
to buy a cow?
你就用那些豆
去买了一头牛?
No, AIbert, I gave him my ring.
不是的, 艾伯特, 我把我的戒指给了他.
Okay,
好,
confining my concIusions
to the pIanet Earth,
不玩了
言归正传,
the cocaine you found
in James HurIey's gas tank
你在詹姆斯·赫尔利的油缸
找到的那些可卡因
was a match to what we found
in Jacques' car
和我们在雅克的车上
找到的是一样的
and Leo's house.
Get the picture?
还有藏在里欧房子里的.
明白了?
Even got the frame.
再明白
不过了.
Handiwork of Leo Johnson,
都是里欧·强生捣的鬼,
currentIy appearing at CaIhoun
MemoriaI HospitaI as Mr. Potato Head.
不过他现在只能躺在考尔宏纪念医院
做大蕃薯了.
The boots are a CircIe Brand
rare work boot.
那双环牌靴子
现在已经很少见了.
Ones we found haven't been worn
or tampered with.
还没穿过
全新的.
The Ietter B from Ronette's finger
朗尼特指甲缝的「B」
was cut from a copy of Flesh World.
It's a perfect match.
是从《肉欲世界》
那里剪下来的.
This particuIar edition features
swingers' cIubs
这期是性交大会俱乐部
专门为那些露毛僻爱好者
for standard poodIe enthusiasts.
而设的特别版.
No comment.
不予置评.
We sent a portrait
of your Iong-haired man
我们查过了
你那个长发男
to every agency from NASA
to DEA and came up empty.
就连太空总署和
缉毒所都找不到.
This cat is in nobody's database.
他的资料.
A man that four of us
have seen here in Twin Peaks.
一个我们四个人都
在双峰镇见过的人会查不到?
Sure.
就是.
Oh, by the way, you were shot
with a WaIther PPK.
哦, 还有, 打你的是
德国产瓦尔特军用手枪.
It's James Bond's gun,
did you know that?
杰·士邦用的那款,
很酷吧?
You're Iooking better today, Coop.
库, 你今天看起来好多了.
Thank you, AIbert. FeeIing better.
谢谢, 艾伯特. 是好多了.
The traiI of the man who shot you
is ice-coId,
那个家伙的手法干净利落
几乎没留下什么痕迹,
but I hoovered some fibers
from the corridor outside your room.
不过还是给我在你房门外的走廊上
找到了一些细纤维.
My ticket out of TroIIeyviIIe.
我买了去查利维尔的票.
I'II be at the Iab, gentIemen.
先回实验室了, 先生们.
- Anything we shouId be working on?
- Yeah.
- 还有什么需要我们跟进的吗?
- 有.
You might practice waIking without
dragging your knuckIes on the fIoor.
你可以练习一下
如何走路才不会摔个狗啃屎.
AIbert, Iet's taIk about knuckIes.
艾伯特, 那我们就来谈谈狗啃屎.
Now, the Iast time,
I knocked you down.
听着, 上次,
打了你.
I feIt bad about it. The next time's
gonna be a reaI pIeasure.
我本来很内疚. 但如果再来一次
我就不会了.
You Iisten to me.
你也给我听着.
WhiIe I wiII admit to
a certain cynicism,
我承认我是个玩世不恭
口没遮拦的人,
the fact is that I'm a naysayer
and hatchet man
我还是个怀疑论者
否定主义者
in the fight against vioIence.
和罪恶克星.
I pride myseIf in taking a punch
很荣幸上次吃你一拳
and I'II gIadIy take another
你要再来一拳吗
because I choose to Iive my Iife
in the company of Gandhi and King.
没关系，来啊
甘地王者与我同在.
My concerns are gIobaI.
春满人间.
I reject absoIuteIy revenge, aggression
and retaIiation.
以暴制暴
冤冤相报何时了啊.
The foundation of such a method...
真爱...
...is Iove.
...是唯一.
I Iove you, Sheriff Truman.
我爱你, 杜鲁门警长.
AIbert's path is
a strange and difficuIt one.
唉，其实艾伯特也不容易
一个有怪癖的天才.
Deputy.
德彪德.
James, you're not
gonna be charged.
詹姆斯, 你不会被起诉的
现在可以走了.
The cocaine we found in your bike
was pIanted.
已经证实那些可卡因
是插赃嫁祸.
- I was trying to teII you that when--
- James,
- 我当时就想告诉你的，其实--
- 詹姆斯,
I don't wanna see you
down here again.
我不想再见到你
被抓到这来了.
Yes, sir.
是的, 先生.
Stop trying to
figure it aII out yourseIf.
不要老是
孤军作战.
Find someone to taIk to.
TaIk to me.
要学会找人商量.
也可以来找我.
Go on home, James.
回家吧, 詹姆斯.
How's it going, Lucy?
怎样了, 露西?
Seventy-five words.
75个词.
Oh, wait a minute, 76.
噢, 等等, 76.
- Seventy-seven.
- Good work, Lucy.
- 77.
- 干的好, 露西.
That's 78.
78.
Agent Cooper asked me to find
as many words as I couId
库珀探员叫我
尽量找出
that contain the Ietters B, T and R.
和B, T ，R有关的词.
Let me see.
I used to be pretty good at this.
我看看.
我以前很在行这个.
My Iunch date is here.
午间约会到了.
This is the date that made Andy
caII in sick?
就是他搞的安迪
要告病假?
Hi, Lucy.
嗨, 露西.
There you are.
我来了.
HeIIo, Dick.
你好, 基巴.
Lucy, I've aIways considered you
to be a woman of Ietters.
露西, 我就知道你是个
有文化的女人.
''Prohibited.''
''禁止.''
I say, I don't beIieve
we've met.
冒昧, 真不敢相信
我们能在这里认识.
Richard Tremayne.
我是理查·车梅恩.
Horne's Department Store.
荷恩百货店的.
Designer Menswear.
男装设计师.
Robot.
我罗伯特.
Did I do something to anger him?
我刚对他有什么失礼的地方吗?
Not that native peopIe don't have
enough reason to be angry, per se.
本质上，一个土着
也没什么值得失礼的吧.
- Let's go to Iunch.
- CapitaI.
- 去吃饭吧.
- 进城吃吧.
We'II go Dutch.
去吃荷兰菜.
So how taII was this guy?
Did his head hit the ceiIing?
那巨人有多高?
有顶到天花板吗?
AImost.
差不多.
I beIieve that the ceiIings in The
Great Northern are at Ieast 1 0 feet taII.
我想大北方酒店的房
至少有10尺高.
At Ieast.
至少有.
I'm sorry.
抱歉.
I hope I'm not interrupting.
来打搅你们了.
That's okay, LeIand.
What's on your mind?
没事, 利兰.
有什么消息吗?
This man.
这个人.
I know him.
我认得.
How do you know him,
LeIand?
你怎么认识的,
利兰?
When I was a IittIe boy,
我那时还是个小孩,
my grandfather had a summer home
up on PearI Lakes.
我爷爷在珍珠湖那里
有一幢避暑山庄.
We used to go there every year.
我们每年都去那里一趟.
- You knew him from there?
- Yes. Yes.
- 你在哪里认识他的?
- 是. 是.
Now, I know that
he wasn't a CheIbert.
现在, 我终于知道
他不是个鬼魂.
They were our neighbors that Iived
on one side.
当时他就住在
我们旁边 .
On the other side
there was a vacant Iot.
那里有一块
空地.
Next to that was a white house.
空地旁有一间白色的房子.
That's where he Iived.
他就住在那里.
Do you remember a name?
你还记得他叫什么吗?
No.
不记得了.
I think...
我想想...
I think it was
Robertson. Robertson.
好像叫
罗伯逊. 罗伯逊.
Robertson.
叫罗伯逊.
Robert. R, T, B. That's what
the Ietters are trying to speII.
罗伯. R, T, B. 这几个字母
原来就是代表这个名字.
Hawk, get up to PearI Lakes, find out
who used to Iive in that white house.
豪克, 快去珍珠湖, 查查
谁在那儿住过.
I'II do what I can.
知道，我尽快.
LeIand, thank you.
利兰, 谢谢你.
- That's vaIuabIe information. Thanks.
- Thank you, LeIand.
- 这消息很重要. 谢谢.
- 感谢你, 利兰.
Something eIse.
哦，还有还有.
He used to fIick matches at me.
他还曾经在我面前玩火柴.
He'd say:
他说:
''You wanna pIay with fire,
IittIe boy?''
''你想玩火吗,
小子?''
That's our man.
他就是我们要找的人 .
Of course, most of the time I keep
my department running Iike a top,
其实, 平常大部分时间
我主管的部门都运作的很正常,
but Christmas--
WeII, that was such a madhouse.
但圣诞节一到--
唉, 就变得乱糟糟的.
Was absoIuteIy
no time for paperwork.
根本没时间
去读文件.
I simpIy had to deveIop a system
to memorize customer orders
我开发了一套简易的
订单记忆系统
using mnemonic triggers.
只要轻轻一按记忆开关.
For instance,
someone Iooking for argyIe socks?
例如,
有客人要找格子短袜?
WeII, that wouId fiIe under A
for ''argyIe,'' subheading S for ''socks.''
好, 只需输入「格」
和「袜」字．
Now, it does get tricky.
现在, 这系统很管用.
A request for a vuIcanized mackintosh,
for instance--
如果要找橡胶雨衣,
比如--
Now, does that fiIe under R
for ''raingear,''
这样, 只要输入
「雨具」
or W for ''waterproof''?
或者「防水」?
My famiIiarity with the inventory
finds me Ieaning towards an R.
马上就会出现
你要找的详细目录.
Lucy, may I ask you something?
露西, 可以问你点事吗?
Do you find it odd that
I don't switch my fork when I eat,
你有没注意到我有点怪
叉子没有换到右边，
that I Iift it to my mouth
with my Ieft hand?
我吃饭时
是用左手的?
My mother caIIs it piIing.
我妈说这是造作.
ActuaIIy, it's not odd at aII.
其实, 也不是很怪.
It's the European way.
欧洲人就这样用叉的.
It's been six weeks, Dick.
You said you were gonna caII.
已经六个星期了, 基巴.
你说过给我电话的.
I know.
我知道.
I Iost your phone number.
你电话我丢了.
I work for the sheriff.
You couId've diaIed 91 1 .
我在警局工作.
你可以打911啊 .
Lucy, I do apoIogize.
I've been so terribIy busy, honestIy.
露西, 真的很抱歉.
我最近忙死了, 真的.
I've hardIy had time to feed my cat.
忙得连猫都没时间喂.
We went out every Thursday night
for three months.
三个月来
我们不每周四晚都见吗.
You made promises to me. You said
you were gonna take me to dinner
你还答应过我.
说要带我去西雅图的
at the Space NeedIe in SeattIe.
太空塔餐厅吃饭的.
Even though you took me to
FamiIy Night at the Pancake PIantation,
虽然你带我去过
潘吉植物园的家庭餐厅,
I stiII couIdn't heIp but think
that it meant something speciaI.
但我还是不觉得
有什么特别的.
When in fact the onIy thing speciaI
we did that night
除了我们做的
那天晚上
was drink two bottIes of champagne
两瓶香槟
and end up on a dispIay bed
in Horne's Home Furnishings!
然后就在荷恩百货店的
家俱陈列室里把事给办了!
I admit it was daring.
That made it exciting.
我承认那晚很大胆.
也让我很兴奋.
StiII, I thought it wouId Iead to more.
Like a phone caII.
的确, 我还以为会有后续.
如给我电话之类.
Lucy, I feeI terribIe you're upset.
ReaIIy I do.
露西, 让你难过我也不好受.
真的.
- Let me make it up to you.
- Like how, for instance?
- 我会补偿的.
- 怎样补, 比如呢?
For starters,
首先,
I know I promised you a new dress
at my 20 percent empIoyee discount.
我会给你买条新裙子
我有店员福利，购物八折优惠.
After Iunch, I'II go right back
吃完饭, 我马上去买
and arrange something with Ms. BoIbo
in women's wear. Very speciaI indeed.
我和女装部的
波尔布太太打个招呼. 给你选特别点的.
Oh, yeah?
噢, 有多特别?
How about a maternity dress!
孕妇装够特别了吧!
Pardon?
什么?
I'm pregnant, Richard.
我怀孕了, 理查.
Pregnant.
怀孕了.
Preggers?
有馅了?
Does Donna seem different to you?
你觉得唐娜最近有什么不同吗?
What do you mean?
什么意思?
WeII, Iike, doesn't her smoking
and stuff bother you?
嗯, 比如, 开始抽烟
或者老烦着你?
She's trying to act, Iike, aII tough
aII of a sudden.
她的举动变的好奇怪, 就像,
忽然变异.
James, you know her
better than I do.
詹姆斯, 你不比我
更了解她吗.
Yeah.
那倒是.
She came to visit
when I was in jaiI and...
她来监狱
看我...
I don't know.
我搞不懂.
What?
什么?
WeII,
唔,
she acted Iike she wanted
她表现得很想
to do it with me
through the bars.
和我亲热
即使隔着铁栏.
She didn't even care
if anybody was around.
她甚至不在乎
有人在旁边.
I don't know.
搞不懂.
It was weird.
反正很怪.
It wasn't Iike her.
都不像她了.
I don't know.
我不知道.
I don't know anything anymore.
我现在什么都搞不懂了.
Sometimes I think I shouId
just get on my bike and go.
有时我真想骑上我的车
一走了之.
James.
詹姆斯.
Running away
won't soIve anything.
逃避
解决不了问题的.
It's gonna be okay.
会好起来的.
Donna, where you been?
You're Iate.
唐娜, 你去哪儿了?
你来晚了.
I met someone
from MeaIs on WheeIs.
我送餐时
认识了一些人.
Those oId foIks must have
some pretty cooI stories.
那些老人家
肯定有很多旧事讲吧.
This was a young man.
是个年轻人.
ReaIIy?
What's wrong with him?
真的?
他为什么需要送餐服务?
You know, it's hard to say.
天知道.
Other than he was bright
and charming, inteIIigent.
反正他聪明又迷人
而且很友善.
CompIeteIy unIike anybody I know.
完全不像某些人.
What's that supposed to mean?
你想说什么?
Why don't you sit here and hoId hands
and try to figure it out.
你们坐在这手拉手
就知道我想说什么了.
That's good, Emory.
真是太好了, 艾默里.
She's ready for her cIose-up now.
现在给她个大特写.
We shouId get rid of her.
我们要干掉她才行.
She knows I sent Laura up here,
she knows her father owns the pIace.
他知道是我把劳拉招进来的,
也发现了这里是她爸的.
With what Ben Horne wiII pay to get
his funked-up IittIe daughter back,
这样他才会付钱
把这傻妞赎回去啊,
I'II buy the bastard out.
我打保票.
Look, I don't wanna Iose my job.
看, 我可不想丢了饭碗.
Honey, if this doesn't work,
you'II Iose a Iot more than your job.
甜心, 如果这都行不通,
丢的可不只是你的工作.
We can't handIe this aIone.
Ben Horne is dangerous.
我们两个应付不来的.
本·荷恩很可怕.
Now, Iisten, you spineIess gasbag,
you are in this up to your shiny pate.
现在, 给我听好了, 你这个软蛋,
你已经别无选择了，地中海头.
Now, stop whining.
少囉嗦.
You do as I teII you, and we'II have
aII the heIp we need.
叫你干啥就干啥, 别的事
我会处理好的.
Look at her.
看看她.
Riding the white tiger.
多享受.
In a few days
she won't wanna come down.
够她受好几天了
好好享受去吧.
Just Iike her daddy did to me.
就像当年她老爸对待我一样.
Now, these babies
are just perfect.
看, 这些宝贝
做工多好.
For heavy fieId work,
and they're extremeIy versatiIe.
下地干重活,
它们绝对没问题.
- DurabIe, with a steeI reinforced toe.
- Not quite right.
- 耐磨耐穿, 脚趾部分还用钢加固了.
- 不太好.
Now, if the department does
any parading,
现在, 如果你们局里
要搞什么活动,
on the Fourth or Veterans Day,
these are your best bet.
像国庆日或退伍军人节,
这款就最合适不过了.
- Nice, huh?
- Yeah.
- 很好吧?
- 是不错.
Add some siIver-trimmed Iaces,
it's a reaI eye-catcher.
还镶了银边,
很养眼吧.
I can see that. But a IittIe outside
my budget, Mr. Gerard.
我知道. 不过对我来说
还是贵了点, 杰勒德先生.
I understand compIeteIy.
完全理解.
- You need something more practicaI.
- Yep.
- 你要实惠点的.
- 对.
A shoe for aII seasons.
一年四季都能穿.
Now, this is more Iike it.
你看, 这双就很合适我.
Yeah. Jim-dandy.
看. 一流.
Very popuIar.
这双很多人买.
The IoveIy thing about--
最好的是--
Mr. Gerard?
杰勒德先生?
Mr. Gerard, you okay?
杰勒德先生, 你没事吧?
I'm sorry.
不好意思.
Sometimes I get
a bit disoriented.
我时不时就
觉得有点头晕.
Can I get you something?
Water?
需要点什么吗?
水
If there's a bathroom,
I have a medication.
有洗手间吗,
我带了药.
Sure. It's right down the haII.
This way.
有. 就在大厅.
这边.
Thanks for coming down, SheIIy.
谢谢你能来, 雪莉.
Sheriff, I'm just gonna say this:
警长, 我准备告诉你:
I know I don't have to, so I'm not
gonna say anything against Leo.
显然我可以不这么做, 但我不想
和里欧对着干.
We're not asking you to.
我们不是叫你对着干.
He's my husband. I don't have
to testify against my husband.
他始终是我丈夫. 我不想
出庭指证他.
WeII, you're not testifying.
You're just giving us a statement.
好, 你可以不出庭.
只要给我们个书面声明就行了.
Doc Hayward says he's too sick.
海沃德医生不说他不行了吗.
What difference does it make?
那还有什么意义?
The difference, SheIIy,
is there's some peopIe injured
听我说, 雪莉,
有人在这次事件里受伤
and there's some peopIe dead.
有人更因此丧命了.
Now, we know Leo started that fire.
现在, 我们已经知道是里欧放的火了.
And we know you were there.
你当时不也在场吗.
I'm not gonna say anything
against him.
我不打算
起诉他.
I Iove him.
我爱他.
Okay, SheIIy, that's fine.
那好, 雪莉, 就这样.
- Thanks for coming in.
- What?
- 谢谢你来.
- 什么?
Oh, I think SheIIy's thought
Iong and hard about this.
哦, 我想雪莉一定考虑
的很长很仔细了.
Maybe someday, with a IittIe Iuck
and some topfIight medicaI attention,
或许某天运气好的话,
第一流的治疗,
you'II have Leo back.
会让里欧醒过来.
The same oId Leo
that you obviousIy stiII Iove.
一个你不离不弃
爱着的老里欧.
Maybe then he'II reaIize what
a wonderfuI person he's married to.
或许他也会意识到
他娶了个多好的老婆啊.
What?
啊?
Thanks again, SheIIy.
再次感谢, 雪莉.
Best of Iuck.
祝你福星高照.
What's going on?
这是怎么回事?
SmeIIs Iike insurance money.
估计和保险金有关.
SheIIy didn't dream this up herseIf.
但雪莉自己不会想到这些.
So who do you think is
puIIing the strings?
那你觉得是谁
在背后捣的鬼?
Harry,
哈里,
that's a damn good question.
问得好.
Bob...
鲍勃...
...I know you're near.
...我知道你就在附近.
I'm after you now.
现在，我追到你了.
- Mr. Horne?
- Tsk tsk. Gotta go, Jerry.
- 荷恩先生?
- 啧, 啧. 先不说了, 杰利.
Mr. Horne, have you heard
anything from your daughter?
荷恩先生, 有你女儿
的消息了吗?
Not since I spoke to
Sheriff Truman yesterday.
没有，从我昨天打电话给杜鲁门警长
到现在还没有.
She phoned me Iast night.
她昨晚给我打了电话.
- From where?
- She didn't say.
- 她在哪?
- 她没说.
She referenced seeing me
in my tuxedo.
她说她见到我穿
晚礼服.
Now, I was wearing a tux here
at the hoteI the night that I was shot.
看, 我在这中枪的那晚
也是穿者晚礼服.
WeII, Iike I toId you,
Audrey's gone missing before
嗯, 正如我告诉你的,
欧蕊以前也有离家出走
on a semi-reguIar basis.
家常便饭了.
So have two other
IocaI girIs recentIy.
但最近那两个女孩
不就这样发生以外的吗.
Mr. Horne, speaking frankIy,
is there troubIe at home?
荷恩先生, 老实说,
是不是家里有麻烦了?
Mr. Cooper,
库珀先生,
do I detect a note of something outside
the scope of professionaI concern?
我什么时候说过需要专业建议了
你是不是有点越界了?
Audrey and I have struck up
an acquaintance.
欧蕊和我
彼此很了解的.
Acquaintance.
彼此了解.
Agent Cooper.
库珀探员.
Let me give you the best advice
that you're gonna get aII week:
倒不如我给你点建议
好让你搞清楚状况吧:
Men faII under the speII
of Audrey's charms
凡是对欧蕊
动脑筋的男人
Iike ducks in a shooting gaIIery.
都只不过是游乐摊位里当靶子的小旱鸭.
And if you don't want a
Ioad of buckshot in your taiI feathers,
如果你不想惹火烧身
做下一个靶子,
may I suggest that you park your jaIopy
outside of somebody eIse's window.
我看你还是识相点
趁早找别人玩去吧.
Mr. Horne, if I've overstepped my
bounds with my concern, I apoIogize.
荷恩先生, 如果你真认为是
我越界了, 我道歉.
I am here
with onIy the best intentions.
我不过是
好心为你提个醒而已.
That is achingIy cIear.
彻底了解.
And not unappreciated.
劳你心了.
I'II put a Iamp in the window,
我会在窗口为欧蕊点个指路灯,
you'II be my first caII
when she comes home to roost.
只要她一回家
我第一时间通知你.
Thank you.
谢谢你.
No, thank you.
不, 应该谢谢你.
WeIcome back.
欢迎回来.
Where am I?
我在哪?
I brought you something.
我带了东西给你.
Open wide.
张开.
EngIish carameIs.
英国焦糖.
Sugar's what you need.
你需要糖分.
- PIease...
- Go sIow, baby.
- 求求你...
- 慢点吃, 宝贝.
Candy's dandy, huh?
味道很棒吧, 呵?
PIenty more where that came from.
别急，还有好多.
My name is Jean.
我叫尚.
Sweet sIeep.
乖乖睡.
FeeI the warmth.
你会觉得很暖和.
That's the man.
就是他.
Oh, my God.
哦, 上帝.
- You know him?
- FBI.
- 你认识他?
- 联邦调查局.
He's FBI. I saw him at the town
meeting after Laura died.
他是联邦调查局的. 劳拉死后
我在镇会议上见过他.
He was up here?
他来过这了?
I want him.
我要他.
Jean RenauIt. Emory,
这是尚·雷诺. 艾默里,
say something weak and fawning.
快来
打个招呼.
Jacques was your brother?
雅克是你弟弟?
And this is my sister.
这个是我妹妹.
Nancy?
南希?
I aIso had a brother, Bernard.
我还有一个兄弟, 叫伯纳德.
This business cost me them both.
我就是为他们而来的.
I toId you we'd have heIp.
看，告诉过你我会处理的吧.
I'm your go-between.
这事我来出面摆平.
The father pays me,
my cut is 30 percent.
赎金我去取,
我拿30%.
The father never know
who snatch his baby.
爸爸永远不会知道
是谁偷了他的宝贝女.
And I get the man
who kiII my brother.
把这个杀我弟的人
交给我处理.
What's his name?
他叫什么名字?
- Cooper.
- 库珀.
And aII you have to do
is bring him to me.
你唯一要做的就是
把他带来给我.
Mr. Horne can maybe do that.
荷恩先生或许能办到.
But you're going to be a big heIp,
aren't you?
但你也会帮个大忙,
不是吗?
Whatever you want--
Want me to do.
无论你要什么--
要我做什么.
The tape of the girI.
Get it now.
那女孩的录像带.
快去拿.
Yes, aII right.
是, 好的.
She goes back north,
她准备回北方,
- or this deaI goes south.
- Jean, teII my sister to behave herseIf,
- 还是回南方.
- 尚, 告诉我姐先管好她自己,
or you'II get mad.
不然她会让你发疯的.
She stays.
她留下来陪我.
You get the money, I get Cooper.
Everybody happy.
你拿钱, 我要库珀.
皆大欢喜.
Of course, we...
当然了, 我们...
We can't Iet the girI Iive now,
不会让那女孩活太久了,
can we?
会吗?
No, no, no. Thanks, Pete.
I appreciate the caII.
不, 不，不. 谢谢, 皮特.
感谢你给我电话.
Harry?
哈里?
Time for a break.
休息一下.
Josie caIIed Pete.
She'II be back tomorrow afternoon.
乔西打电话给皮特了.
她明天下午回镇.
Great. Let's bring her in.
好极了. 传唤她.
Coop, I need a favor.
库, 帮我个小忙.
I'd Iike to see her first.
AIone.
我想先见见她.
单独.
Harry, we can't Iet personaI feeIings
interfere with our work.
哈里, 我们不能让私人感情
影响到工作.
Easier said than done.
说的比做的容易啊.
TaIk to her.
Bring her in.
那好吧.
晚些再传唤她.
You know there's a chance that
she's not invoIved with any of this.
你明白吗，很有可能她
和整件事无关的.
Harry, you have my bIessing.
哈里, 我祝福你.
PearI Lakes.
珍珠湖.
There's a vacant Iot
next to the PaImer house.
那里确实有一块空地
在帕尔默家旁边.
Next to that there's a white house
aII boarded up.
隔壁的白房子
全都锁上了.
- MaiIbox, no name on it.
- TitIe check?
- 邮箱, 没有姓名.
- 人口资料?
County's working on it. Power and
Lights are searching their records.
正在县城里查呢. 电力和电灯公司
也正在翻查他们的记录.
- How soon before we know?
- Morning, earIiest.
- 结果要多久?
- 最快也要明天早晨.
Hawk, you haven't seen Mr. Gerard,
have you?
豪克, 你刚见到杰勒德先生吗,
看到他吗?
- Shoe saIesman?
- The one-armed man?
- 鞋子推销员?
- 独臂人?
He came in to show me
some sampIes.
他今天来给我
看些样品.
The one-armed man was here?
独臂人来过这?
Yeah, he got faint
and had to go to the bathroom.
是, 他不舒服
去了洗手间.
Never came back.
之后就没回来了.
Harry, remember in my dream?
The one-armed man knew Bob.
哈里, 还记得我的梦?
独臂人认识鲍勃.
What's going on?
怎么了?
''Without chemicaIs, he points.''
''不要用药, 他就会指引你.''
The Giant's third cIue.
巨人的第三个暗示.
Harry, we've got to find
the one-armed man.
哈里, 我们必须找到
独臂人.
Is that reaIIy necessary, doc?
真的需要这样吗, 医生?
It's for her own protection, Ed.
是为了好好保护她, 艾德.
She ripped two pair
of Ieather restraints Iast night
她昨晚轻易就扯裂了
两条手腕固定皮带
Iike tissue paper.
I ran a bIood test.
就像撕纸巾一样.
我做了个血液测试.
She's pumping out more adrenaIine
than a wiIdcat weII.
她的肾上腺素就像
初探油井一样不断飙升.
Never seen anything Iike it.
从未见过这样的.
Now, your being here
may quiet her.
现在, 你在这儿
或许能安抚一下她.
TaIk to her. Maybe sing.
She got a favorite song?
和她说说话. 唱个歌什么的.
她有特别喜欢的歌吗?
Favorite song?
特别喜欢的歌?
Beats a trip to Lourdes.
唱「卢尔德巡逻之旅」怎样.
Okay.
好.
But if I'm gonna sing to her, doc,
I'd rather it was just the two of us.
不过我要对她唱歌的话，医生,
最好还是我们两个人单独相处吧.
I'II cIose the door behind me.
那我走了.
Nadine?
纳丁?
Doc says I shouId sing a song for you.
医生说我应该给你唱首歌.
I'm sorry, honey.
I'm not sure what you'd Iike to hear.
对不起, 甜心.
我不知道你喜欢听什么.
On top of Old Smokey
老护林熊头上
All covered with snow
一头白雪
l lost my true lover
我失去了真正的爱人
A-courtin' too slow
追悔莫及
Courting's a pleasure
相恋时快乐
Parting's a grief
离别时神伤
A false-hearted lover
一个虚情假意的恋人
ls worse than a thief
比贼还坏
Good God.
老天哪.
You're a jack and l'm a jack
And Steeplejacks are we
你是千斤顶 我也是千斤顶
我们都是修塔工
And when we climb up to the top
当我们爬上高高的塔尖
The cry is victory!
放声高呼「胜利」
V-l-C-T-O-R-Y!
V-I-C-T-O-R-Y!
Vi--
胜利--
Hi, Eddie.
嗨, 小艾艾.
Did you come by
to pick me up?
你来接我
回家吗?
Doc Hayward says
tonsiIIitis or no tonsiIIitis,
海沃德医生说了
有没有扁桃腺炎,
I can go to cheerIeading tryouts.
我都可以去参加啦啦队长选拔赛.
CheerIeader tryouts?
啦啦队长选拔赛?
WeII, I'm a senior, Eddie.
啊, 我可是高年班生, 小艾艾.
You know what they say.
你知道他们说什么吗?
You're onIy 1 8 once.
人生只有一次18岁.
Dr. Jacoby?
杰柯比医生?
Gents.
Come on in.
先生们.
快进来.
This is my wife, EoIani.
这是我太太, 伊欧莱丽.
She Iives at our pIace in HanaIei.
她住在哈纳雷.
We're-- WeII, we're practicing
a kind of creative kahuna heaIing.
我们--嗯,正在练习一种
自创的卡哈纳治疗法.
- How do you do?
- Ma'am.
- 你好吗?
- 夫人.
Are you ready to be hypnotized?
可以开始催眠了吗?
Yes, yes.
I've been under many times.
是, 可以了.
我已经试过很多次了.
This is the autosuggestion program
that I use.
这是我用的
自我暗示程序.
EoIani, start the tape, pIease.
伊欧莱丽, 请开始播放吧.
Sheriff Truman.
杜鲁门警长.
WouId you hoId this stone, pIease,
at the end of the bed there?
可以请你拿着这块石头,
站在床头吗?
Great. Just--
好. 往这边一点--
Yes.
对.
Okay, Agent Cooper.
I'm ready.
好, 库珀探员.
来吧.
''You are standing on
a smooth, green carpet of grass.
「你站在平整葱郁
的绿草地上」.
The baII is 1 5 feet from the hoIe.
球离洞15尺.
Beyond the green,
two pristine white sand traps
草地远处,
有两个原始的沙坑
and a IiIy-fiIIed pond yawn out
towards the emeraId fairway.
还有一个开满百合的水池
向着翡翠一样碧绿的球道.
The hoIe seems to sIowIy drift away
across the green
洞越来越大
穿过草地
towards the pond,
carried by the summer wind.
向池边扩张,
一阵微风吹来.
The green grows Iarger and Iarger.
草地也越来越大.
The green enguIfs you,
把你吸了进去,
enveIoping you
in a soft bIanket of peace.
以无限温柔的
宁静将你包裹着.
Harry.
哈里.
You stroke the baII.
你打球.
It drifts towards the hoIe
and gentIy drops in its center.''
它慢慢滚向洞口
轻轻的落入洞中.''
Can you hear me, Dr. Jacoby?
你能听见吗, 杰柯比医生?
Yes.
是的.
You're in your hospitaI room.
In the room is Jacques RenauIt.
你在医院的病房里.
雅克·雷诺在那里躺着.
Do you smeII anything?
Burned engine oiI?
你闻到什么了?
烧焦的机油味?
I smeII engine oiI at the park.
我在公园闻到机油味.
Air is fiIIed with it.
空气里都是.
AII right, we're going back to your room
at the hospitaI now.
那好, 我们现在回到
医院里.
Does anyone come into the room?
有人进来过吗?
Nurses,
护士,
Doc Hayward.
海沃德医生.
You, Sheriff Truman.
你, 杜鲁门警长.
What happens after we Ieave?
我们走后发生了什么?
I dream I'm at Hanauma Bay.
我梦见我在哈瑞马湾.
I'm juggIing coconuts at a Iuau.
我在烤猪野宴上变魔术.
The guests are aII Nigerians.
客人全是尼日利亚人.
AII right.
很好.
Does anyone eIse come into the room,
Iater that night?
那晚之后,
还有其他人来过病房吗?
The sound of the tape ripping
wakes me up.
撕胶带的声音
把我吵醒了.
I see a piIIow going over his face.
我看见他的脸被枕头捂着.
He's making this sound.
他发出这种声音.
Almost like a dog barking.
和狗叫差不多.
Jacques stops moving.
之后雅克就不动了.
I Iook up to see
who's hoIding the piIIow.
我于是抬头看
是谁拿着枕头.
Who is it?
是谁?
Do you see who it is?
你看到是谁了吗?
I know him.
我认识他.
Hi.
嗨.
This is from HaroId Smith.
这是哈罗德·史密斯送你的.
Sorry I haven't been out
to see you since the funeraI,
对不起，葬礼之后我一直
都没来看你,
but things have been
pretty strange.
但事情变得
很奇怪.
So were you sIeeping with
this guy HaroId or what?
你和这个哈罗德睡过了
还干过别的什么吗?
He seems pretty nice.
他看起来不错.
Kind of an oddbaII.
怪人一个.
AIthough, I guess anyone
can start to seem Iike that
当然,但你考得够近
每个人
when you Iook cIose enough.
都会开始显得古怪.
We need to taIk.
我们要谈谈.
Maybe you aIready know
about me and James.
或许你已经知道
我和詹姆斯的事了.
But anyway, after you died,
we kind of got together.
总之, 你死后,
我们就在一起了.
This isn't something
I feeI Iike I have to expIain to you
其实这事我也没必要
非得向你解释
because you probabIy knew
how we feIt before we did.
你或许早就了解
我们的感受了.
How can you be so smart
about things Iike that...
真搞不懂
对这个你这么在行...
...and so stupid
about so much eIse?
...对别的事
你又是那么愚蠢?
I'm mad at you.
我生你气了.
When it was you and me
and James, it kind of worked.
你和我，还有詹姆斯
当时3个人多好啊.
Now you're gone.
现在你走了.
I Iove James.
我爱詹姆斯.
And it's a mess.
乱套了.
Your cousin Maddy's here,
你表妹马蒂来了,
and I think there's something going on
between the two of them.
我总觉得她和詹姆斯
之间有点那个.
And I'm afraid I'm gonna end up
Iosing both of you.
我好怕最终
会失去你们2个.
I wanted so much to be Iike you,
Laura.
我多想和你一样,
劳拉.
To have your strength
and your courage.
像你一样有力量
和勇气.
But Iook what it did.
但你看.
Look what it did to you.
看它对你做了什么.
As much as I Iove you, Laura,
正如我对你的爱, 劳拉,
most of the time we were trying
to soIve your probIems.
大部分时间我们都在
解决你的麻烦.
And you know what?
We stiII are.
你知道吗?
现在还是.
Not mine or James' or Maddy's.
Yours.
不是我的詹姆斯的，也不是马蒂的.
你的.
You're dead, Laura, but your probIems
keep hanging around.
你死了, 劳拉, 但你的麻烦
还缠着我们不放.
It's aImost Iike they didn't bury you
deep enough!
似乎他们还把你埋的
不够深!
James.
詹姆斯.
I'm Iooking for Donna.
I can't find her.
找唐娜去了. 但找不到她.
I just gotta taIk to somebody.
我需要找个人谈谈.
What's wrong, James?
怎么了, 詹姆斯?
She came home.
她回来了.
Who?
谁?
My mom was aII Ioaded.
She was aII screwed up.
我妈又喝个烂醉了.
她太糟糕了.
God, I hate her.
天, 我恨她.
James, no.
詹姆斯, 别.
God, you're on fire.
天啊, 你好热.
HoId me.
抱我.
Oh, my God.
哦, 我的天啊.
Donna.
唐娜.
Donna!
唐娜!
Why?!
为什么?!
AII I did was come to a funeraI.
我只来参加葬礼.
And it's Iike I feII into a dream.
却像跌入了梦境.
It's Iike peopIe think
大家都觉得
I'm Laura.
我是劳拉.
And I'm not.
但我不是.
- I'm nothing Iike Laura.
- It's so hard, I know.
- 而且一点也不像劳拉.
- 太难为你了, 我明白.
I know, sweetheart.
I know.
我明白, 宝贝.
我明白.
AII I know is that Laura
was my cousin,
对我而言
劳拉是我表姐,
and I Ioved her and she died.
我爱她，她死了.
I don't know anything eIse.
除此之外，我什么都不知道了.
You just want Iife to be the way
it was before.
你只是希望生活能
和以前一样.
- Yeah.
- So do I.
- 是.
- 我也是.
We aII do.
我们都是.
And try as we might,
it just won't cooperate, wiII it?
我们都不想改变,
但事与愿违, 不是吗?
No.
嗯.
Oh, baby.
哦, 宝贝.
If Iife couId onIy be Iike
those summers up at...
如果生活可以重来
回到在珍珠湖度过的...
...PearI Lakes.
...那些夏季.
LeIand?
利兰?
The door was open.
门没锁.
LeIand...
利兰...
What is it?
出什么事了?
LeIand, you're under arrest
for the murder of Jacques RenauIt.
利兰, 你因谋杀雅克·雷诺
要被逮捕了.
I'm sorry, I didn't know
where eIse to go.
对不起, 我不知道
还有那里可以去.
Donna.
What's wrong?
唐娜.
出什么事了吗?
I don't even know if I want to
taIk about it, I feeI so stupid.
我甚至不知道应不应该说
我觉得好傻.
SIow down.
别急.
Sit down.
先坐.
I keep teIIing myseIf
that he's confused,
我一直安慰自己说
他只是混淆了而已,
but how much Ionger
am I supposed to think that?
但我不知道
还能说服自己多久?
- James HurIey?
- Yeah.
- 詹姆斯·赫尔利?
- 嗯.
Just when I thought I had it
aII figured out.
但我以为所有事
都被解决了.
Why do I even care?
Why shouId I?
我到底在乎什么?
为什么我要这样?
WeII, you care
because you care for him.
嗯, 你在乎
是因为你爱他.
- Don't you?
- I wish I didn't. I just want it to stop.
- 不是吗?
- 真希望我没爱过他. 我好想停下来.
First, you have to stop.
你先冷静点.
Hey, what was it she
used to say?
嘿, 她以前
怎么说来着?
''Donna Madonna,
there's aIways manana.''
''唐娜 麦唐娜,
总是笑哈哈.''
How did you know that?
你怎么会这个的?
- I'II get you something to drink, okay?
- Okay.
- 我去拿点东西给你喝, 好吗?
- 好.